Guide to the Henry Guerlac papers, 1922-1981
Guerlac, Henry papers, 1922-1981
- Series XXIII: Newton: Color and light
  - Biernson - Indigo in the Spectrum (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Borelli (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Boss: Newton and Russia (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - V.J. Bourke: Will in Western Thought (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Boyer, Newton on Polar Coordinates (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Boyle, Robert (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Briggs, William (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Briggs, William: Nova Visionis Theoria (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Charleton (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Clarke, Samuel (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Clarke, Samuel (1675-1729) (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - I.B. Cohen, miscellany (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Cohen: Versions of Isaac Newton's first published paper (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Cole, Theron: Newton's Chemistry (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Desaguliers (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Descartes (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Dobbs, B.J. (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Dollond (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Honoratus Fabri: Dialogi, 1669 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Fahrenheit (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Franklin's Experiments (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Galston, William: Hooke-Newton Controversy (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Gassendi (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Gauger: Letter on Light (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - O. Gingerich: "Great Inequality" (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - S'Gravesand (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Grimaldi (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Gruner, Shirley: Newton and Goethe, "Defending Father Lucas" (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Haas--Antike Lichttheorien (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - David Halm: "Hellenistic Theories of Visions" (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - A. Rupert Hall (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Halley, Edmond (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - W.B. Hardy: capillarity (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Huygens on Halos (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Hanson "Waves, Particles, and Newton's `Fits'" (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Harris, Joseph: "A Treatise of Optics" (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Heimann, Peter (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Hobbes: Elements of Philosophy (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Helmholtz: Optique physiologique (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Hesse, Mary: "Hooke's Philosophical Algebra" (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - T. Holtsmark: Experimentum Crucis (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Hooke, Robert (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Hooke, Micrographia (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Hooke's Lectures on Light, 1681 (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - Horsley notes, 1782 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Iltis, Carolyn (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Letter from T. Jefferson to James Madison, 19 July 1788 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Joyce paper on Particle Theory (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - Joyce and Joyce: Descartes, Newton and Snell's Law (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - Jordan on Newton, 1799, 1800 (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - Keill and Freind (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Koyre and Cohen: Newton and the Leibniz-Clark Correspondence (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Koyre and Cohen: Missing Tanquam (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - Kretzmann on Locke (Semantics) (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - Kubrin: Newton's Cosmos (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - Tom Kuhn: Newton's 31st Query (Box 19, Folder 56)
  - Leibniz-Hartsoeker and Leibniz Theodicee (Box 19, Folder 57)
  - Lichtenstein: Henry More (Box 19, Folder 58)
  - Line or Lime ? ( l'Histoire des Mathematiques) (Box 19, Folder 59)
  - Locke on Words (Box 19, Folder 60)
  - Lohne on Newton (Box 19, Folder 61)
  - Lohne and Sticker (Box 19, Folder 62)
  - Lucretuis et al (Box 19, Folder 63)
  - Lucas (Box 19, Folder 64)
  - Macrobius and Martianus (Box 19, Folder 65)
  - Magirus on Color (Box 19, Folder 66)
  - Mamiani (Box 19, Folder 67)
  - Ernan McMullin: Newton on Matter and Activity (Box 19, Folder 68)
  - Malebrande (Box 19, Folder 69)
  - Perry Miller: New England Mind (Box 19, Folder 70)
  - A.A. Mills on Newton's Prism (Box 19, Folder 71)
  - d'Ocagne's l'Histoire de la Nomographie (Box 19, Folder 72)
  - Phillips-Kersey: New World of Words (Box 19, Folder 73)
  - Plato on Vision and Color (Box 19, Folder 74)
  - J. Priestley on Newton's Opticks (Box 19, Folder 75)
  - F.E.L. Priestley: Clarke-Leibniz Controversy (Box 19, Folder 76)
  - Ray, John (Box 19, Folder 77)
  - Sailor, D. B.: Moses and Atomism (Box 19, Folder 78)
  - Rizzetti (Box 19, Folder 79)
  - Roemer and Velocity of Light (Box 19, Folder 80)
  - Ronchi (Box 19, Folder 81)
  - Rosenfeld (Box 19, Folder 82)
  - Singer, et al on Spectacles and Medieval Optics (Box 19, Folder 83)
  - Seneca, Natural Questions (Box 19, Folder 84)
  - Shea on Gassendi's Atomism (Box 19, Folder 85)
  - Steuwer: Newton on Diffraction (Box 19, Folder 86)
  - Sherburne, Edward: Sphere of Manilius (Box 19, Folder 87)
  - E.W. Strong on Barrow and Newton (Box 19, Folder 88)
  - E.W. Strong: Newton's "Mathematical Way" (Box 19, Folder 89)
  - Syfret on Royal Society (Box 19, Folder 90)
  - Thackray, Arnold (Box 19, Folder 91)
  - Thompson, David: Medieval Painting (Indigo) (Box 19, Folder 92)
  - Toland, John (Box 19, Folder 93)
  - Turnbull on Samuel Hartlib (Box 19, Folder 94)
  - Tyndell on the Blue of Sky (Box 19, Folder 95)
  - Vassius, Isaac (Box 19, Folder 96)
  - D.P. Walker (Box 19, Folder 97)
  - C. Webster: Review of Purver (Box 19, Folder 98)
  - Westfall on Newton's Opticks (Box 19, Folder 99)
  - Whiteside (Box 19, Folder 100)
  - Whiteside, Conversation with (Box 19, Folder 101)
  - Whittaker, Sir E. on Aether (Box 19, Folder 102)
  - Thomas Willis: Anatomy of the Brain (Box 19, Folder 103)
  - Willis, T.: De Fermentatione (Box 19, Folder 104)
  - Young, Thomas (Box 19, Folder 105)
- Series XXIV: 17th-Century figures
  - 17th Century Figures--Apocalypse of St. John (Box 19, Folder 106)
  - Adrian, Lord: Newton's Rooms (Box 19, Folder 107)
  - Affinity Theory (Box 19, Folder 108)
  - Alhazen (Box 19, Folder 109)
  - Ampere (Box 19, Folder 110)
  - Aristotle on Light and Color (Box 19, Folder 111)
  - Atmosphere: Height of (Box 19, Folder 112)
  - Auzout and Star Dimensions (Box 19, Folder 113)
  - Badcock (Box 19, Folder 114)
  - Bailey: The Greek Atomists (Box 19, Folder 115)
  - Ball, W.W. Rouse: Essay on Newton's Principia (Box 19, Folder 116)
  - Barnes, Jonathan: The Pre-Socratic Philosophers (Box 19, Folder 117)
  - J. Barrow and Newton (Box 19, Folder 118)
  - Bishop Berkeley on Color (Box 19, Folder 119)
  - Bologna (Bononian) Stone (Box 19, Folder 120)
  - Chariots: Samuel E. Hill (Box 19, Folder 121)
  - History of Science Society (Box 19, Folder 122)
- Series XXV: Newton's Opticks: Drafts, photocopies of Newton's editions, notes
  - Newtonianism Without Newton (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Can There be Colors in the Dark? (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Colors in the Dark (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Sources for Lavoisier paper, 1770-1772 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Reviews of Opticks (Box 20, Folder 5-7)
  - The New Image of Isaac Newton (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Introduction: Draft (Box 20, Folder 9-12)
  - Newton in France (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - "Newton, God and Gravitation," Alfred University, Apr. 20, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - New Light on Newton's Opticks, Cornell Physics Colloquium, Feb. 24, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Areas for Further Newtonian Studies, 1977-1978 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - "Can We Date Newton's Early Optical Experiments?" (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - "Can We Date Newton's Early Optical Experiments?" final version (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Cudworth and Newton (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Pere Sebastian (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Remond de Montmert's reprint of Newton's De Quadratura Curvarum (Columbia Univ. copy) (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Reaumur letter (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Pierre Coste's Introduction to Optique (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Notes from Proces Verbaux: Solar eclipse of 1715 - Louville and Geoffray (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Coste's Translation of Optical Approbation (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Royal Society of London Journal Book, June 1714-Apr. 1720 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Newton and Optics - Clarke and Toland (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Newton's Opticks, Second English Edition, Book I, 1718 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Newton's Opticks, Second English Edition, Books II and III, 1718 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Newton's Opticks, Fourth English Edition, Book I, 1730 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Newton's Opticks, Fourth English Edition, Books II and III, 1730 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Newton's Opticks, Second Edition, Book I, 1719 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Newton's Opticks, Second Edition, Books II and III, 1719 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Opticks, Ed. Samuel Horsley, Book I (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Opticks, Ed. Samuel Horsley, Book II (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Opticks, Ed. Samuel Horsley, Book III (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Newton's Philosophy of Nature (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Newton (Box 20, Folder 38-39)
  - Newton--General notes (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Newton (Box 20, Folder 41-42)
- Series XXVI: Newton's Opticks: Notes, preliminary working copies, photocopies, and galley proofs
  - Photos for Opticks Edition (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Illustrations (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Illustrations for Introduction to Opticks (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Appendices (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Newton's Opticks, Second English Edition, Book I, 1717 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Newton's Opticks, Second English Edition, Books II and III, 1717 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Notes for Opticks, Book I (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Opticks, Book II (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Opticks, Book III, Part I (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Opticks, Book III (Box 21, Folder 10-ll)
  - Newton (Box 21, Folder 12-13)
  - Stylistic Matters in Notes (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Fore-matter (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Old Text and Notes (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Bibliographical Key - Pages for Correction (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Corrections to be made (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Opticks edition - Text and Notes (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Bechler, Zev (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Newton Bibliography (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Contemporary Newtonian Research (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Opticks, Preliminary working copy (Box 21, Folder 23-26)
  - Opticks, Book I - Galley Proofs (Box 21, Folder 27-35)
  - Opticks, Book II - Galley Proofs (Box 22, Folder 1-7)
- Series XXVII: Lavoisier: Photocopies and drafts
  - Astronomy, A-G (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Astronomy, H-Z (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - "Lavoisier and the Chemistry of Life: An Exploration of Scientific Creativity," Frederic Lawrence Holmes (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Lavoisier M.S. - Reflexions etc., 1772 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Notes from secondary works on Lavoisier (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Lavoisier Bibliography - Secondary Notes (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Lavoisier (Box 22, Folder 14-19)
- Series XXVIII: Typescript lectures and photocopied articles
  - J. Mittlestrass: Methodological Elements of Keplerian Astronomy (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - R. Westman: Kepler's Theory of Hypothesis and the "Realist Dilemma" (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - G. Buchdahl: Methodological Aspects of Kepler's Theory of Refraction (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Explanation in the Natural and Social Sciences by George Henrik von Wright, Cornell Lectures, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 2-4)
- Series XXIX: History of Science Society, Isis matters, Sarton Medal awards
  - History of Science Society, 1958-1959 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
  - Isis matters, 1955-1959 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Isis, 1953-1960 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - History of Science Society, 1962-1965 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Finance Committee, 1953-1960 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Isis Finances (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Agenda, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Letters of Consideration, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Other Candidates, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - U.S. National Committee, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Publicity Committee, 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Membership Cards (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Secretary of Society, 1958-1959 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - George Sarton Foundation, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Isis, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Sarton Medal, 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - U.S. National Committee, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Organizational Material, 1957-1960 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - History of Science Society Meetings, 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Sarton Foundation, 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - President's Official Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Schuman Prize Committee, 1957-1960 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - George Sarton Foundation, 1957-1959 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Donors and Possible Donors, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Emergency Fund, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Council Meeting and Agenda, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Committee Appointments, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Committee Appointments, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Sarton Medal, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Relations with Other Societies, 1957-1959 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - Representatives and Delegates to Learned Societies, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - Metropolitan New York Sections, 1953-1960 (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - Minutes of Council Meeting, 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - Historian of Society, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - Finance Committee, 1953-1957 (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - Pfizer Project, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - Chas. Pfizer & Co., Inc., 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 39)
  - Statutes of the History of Science Society, 1952-1959 (Box 24, Folder 40)
  - Presidency (account 2125), 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1956 (Box 24, Folder 42-44)
  - Editorial Committee, 1954-1957 (Box 24, Folder 45)
  - Sarton Medal, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 46)
  - Meeting, Dec. 1949 (Box 24, Folder 47-48)
  - Meeting--New York, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 49)
  - Meeting--Cleveland, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 50)
  - Program Committee, 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 51)
  - U.S. National Committee, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 52)
  - Social Science Research Council ? Joint Committee on the History and Sociology of Science, 1955-1957 (Box 24, Folder 53)
  - Critical Bibliography, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 54)
  - Isis Editorial Board, 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 55)
  - Isis, 1952-1956 (Box 24, Folder 56)
  - Bibliographical Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 57)
- Series XXX: Bowman committee, 1944-1945
  - Baltimore Meeting, Mar. 1945 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Summary Statement of Recommendations of the Bowmann Committee, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Early Notes before Bowman Committee (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Recommendations of Previous Committees (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Notes and Outlines for Reports (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Efforts of the Secretariat, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Material prepared and distributed by the Secretariat, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - I.I. Rabi - Sub-committee No. 3 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Principle Documents and Minutes, 1944-1945 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Duplicate Material (Box 25, Folder 11)
- Series XXXI: Personal correspondence: Alphabetical, 1939-1975
  - Anchor, Robert (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Applebaum, Wilbur, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Eleanor Belding, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Uno Boklund, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Breiseth, Christopher (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Alain Brieux re Lavoisier (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Brinton, Crane, Society of Fellows, 1939-1952 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Harcourt Brown (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Leslie Burlingame, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - le comte de Chabrol, 1966-1969 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Chazelles, Mlle, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Bernard Cohen, 1942-1974 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Bernard Cohen, 1942-1974 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Stephen Cole, 1960-1961 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Cole, William, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - James B. Conant (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Rowena Connell, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Lamont DuP. Copeland, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - Dobbs, Betty Jo (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Duveen, Dennis, 1957-1967 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Eyles, V.A.: "The evolution of a chemist," James Hall (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - Farrar, Lloyd, 1956-1958 (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Foote, George (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - Fric, Rene, 1962-1968 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Dr. John Fulton, 1947-1952 (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - Galbraith, J.K. (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Gough, Jerry (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Hahn, Roger (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - Willy Hartner (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - Heilbrunn (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - C. Doris Hellman, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 42)
  - Henderson, L.J., 1935 (Box 25, Folder 43)
  - Brooke Hindle, 1958-1961 (Box 25, Folder 44)
  - Hughes, Stuart (Box 25, Folder 45)
  - George Johnson (Box 25, Folder 46)
  - Kauffman, George, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 47)
  - Kirker, Milton (Box 25, Folder 48)
  - G. Kersaint (Box 25, Folder 49)
  - Fred Kilgour, 1950-1953 (Box 25, Folder 50)
  - King, W.J., 1955-1963 (Box 25, Folder 51)
  - King, W.J., 1955-1963 (Box 25, Folder 52)
  - Koyre, Alexander, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 53)
  - K, 1954-1955 (Box 25, Folder 54)
  - Kraus re Lavoisier handwriting, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 55)
  - Laistner, Wolf, 1935, 1941 (Box 25, Folder 56)
  - Marsak, Leonard, 1960-1961 (Box 25, Folder 57)
  - Miller, Alvin, 1955-1961 (Box 25, Folder 58)
  - Miller, Genevieve, 1954-1957 (Box 25, Folder 59)
  - Mosely, Philip E., 1938 (Box 25, Folder 60)
  - Myren, Richard Taylor, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 61)
  - Needham, Joseph (Box 25, Folder 62)
  - Notestein, Wallace, 1936 (Box 25, Folder 63)
  - Osborn, James M., 1940-1942 (Box 25, Folder 64)
  - Panofsky, Erwin, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 65)
  - Perrin, Carl, 1966-1972 (Box 25, Folder 66)
  - Perry, Ralph (Box 25, Folder 67)
  - George Washington Platt, 1952-1953 (Box 25, Folder 68)
  - Dr. Alexander Pogo, 1946-1949 (Box 25, Folder 69)
  - Jacob Price - Tobacco, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 70)
  - Rhoda Rappaport (Box 25, Folder 71)
  - Reingold, Nathan, 1959-1960 (Box 25, Folder 72)
  - Roller, Duane, 1958-1961 (Box 25, Folder 73)
  - Rosinski, Herbert, 1942 (Box 25, Folder 74)
  - Santillana, George, 1940-1950 (Box 25, Folder 75)
  - Sarton, George, 1939-1952 (Box 25, Folder 76)
  - Sarton's Seminar in the History of Science and Learning, ca., 1930-1931 (Box 25, Folder 77)
  - Lucien Scheler, 1967-1970 (Box 25, Folder 78)
  - Dorothy Schullian (Box 25, Folder 79)
  - Schuman, Henry S., 1946-1953 (Box 25, Folder 80)
  - Shear, David, 1959-1960 (Box 25, Folder 81)
  - Richard Shryock, 1941-1965 (Box 25, Folder 82)
  - Singer, Dorothea Waley and Charles, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 83)
  - Bob Silliman, 1959-1961 (Box 25, Folder 84)
  - Smeaton, William, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 85)
  - Stahlman--Treasurer, 1958-1961 (Box 25, Folder 86)
  - Robert Stauffer (Box 25, Folder 87)
  - Martin Staum re Cabanis and Stahl, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 88)
  - Dorothy Stimson, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 89)
  - N. Storer, 1957-1959 (Box 25, Folder 90)
  - Sumner, James B., 1935 (Box 25, Folder 91)
  - Temkin, Owsei (Box 25, Folder 92)
  - Thackray, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 93)
  - Vuillemin, Jules, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 94)
  - Rod Whetstone, Cecil Schneer, Leonard Marsak, 1955-1959 (Box 25, Folder 95)
  - Williams, Pearce, 1955-1961 (Box 25, Folder 96)
  - Woolf, Harry, 1958-1962 (Box 25, Folder 97)
  - Youschkevitch, A. (Box 25, Folder 98)
  - Zilsel, Edgar, 1942 (Box 25, Folder 99)
- Series XXXII: Chronological correspondence: 1940-1975
  - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Personal - College (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - American History Association Meeting in Chicago, 1941 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - University Press--History of Science Series, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Princeton Conference, Dec. 1947 (Box 26, Folder 10-11)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 26, Folder 13-14)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Donald C. Mckay--Prentice Hall, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Ninth Historical Conference, Paris, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 18-19)
  - Conference on Modern France, Princeton, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - History of Science Meeting, Cleveland, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 21-22)
  - Rockefeller Grant, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 23-24)
  - Comments on Report, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - History of Science Society, 1952 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Meeting of History of Science Association, Apr. 1952 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - History of Science Meeting, Washington, D.C., 1952 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence on Citations françaises, 1952 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1953 (Box 26, Folder 34-36)
  - Princeton, 1953 (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 38-40)
  - Travel to Europe, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 42-43)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 44)
  - Insurance - Correspondence and Receipts, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - "A Note on Lavoisier's Scientific Education", 1956 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - "Joseph Priestley's First Papers on Gases", 1956 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 6-7)
  - "A Case of Identity: Macquart or Macquer?", 1957 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Comments on papers of Cyril Smith and Marie Boas, Sept. 1957 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Wisconsin Meeting - Summer, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 12-15)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 16-19)
  - Spanish-French Trip, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Colloque of History of 18th Century Chemistry, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 22-26)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - C.D. Hellman - Vita (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Howard Appointment, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 31-32)
  - Second Corning Conference, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 33-34)
  - European Trip, July 1961 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - John Howard Library, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - Faculty Research Grant, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 37)
  - University of Colorado, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 39-41)
  - French Trip, 1962-1963 (Box 27, Folder 42)
  - Applications for Fellowships, 1962-1963 (Box 27, Folder 43)
  - National Science Foundation Grant, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 2-4)
  - Harry Woolf series, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Behavioral Sciences Newsletter, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Russian Exchange, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Publishers' Expression of Interest, 1963-1965 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Tom Settle, 1963-1966 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - History of Chemistry Division of American Chemical Society, 1963-1966 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 11-15)
  - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - International Congress - Final Report, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Dictionary of Scientific Biography (Box 28, Folder 18-19)
  - Professors-at-Large (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - National Science Foundation Grant (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 22-28)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - History of Radar by Charles Susskind (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Committee on Professors-at-Large (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Sweet Briar, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - French Trip, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - Dictionary of Scientific Biography, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 34-36)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 37-38)
  - Annals of Science, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 39)
  - Ithaca Festival, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 40-42)
  - Festival--Education Program, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 43-44)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 1-5)
  - Hull Publication Committee, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - XII Congres International d'Histoire des Sciences--Paris, Aug. 1968 (Box 29, Folder 8)